Deshdeep Srivastava

+91 80040 24993 | deshdeep.srivastava@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/deshdeep-srivastava | github.com/deshdeep-srivastava

SUMMARY

With nearly 2 years of industry working experience, I have developed a strong skill set in delivering projects and ensuring their proper functionality and reliability. I also have expertise in Python, SQL, MS Excel and foundational knowledge of R, which are critical for data analysis and visualization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, Power BI, R

Libraries & Tools: MS Excel, Tkinter, Pandas, BeautifulSoup, Git

PROJECTS

Cricket Scoreboard

GUI based Project

Python, VS Code, Tkinter

- Developed an interactive GUI Scoreboard using Tkinter.
- User need to input only a single value, either the run scored or a wicket fallen.
- · Implemented logic to calculate score changes based on user input.

Sales Dashboard

Power BI

Data Cleaning, Data Manipulation

- Developed an interactive sales dashboard for comprehensive data exploration and analysis.
- · Advanced parameters enable granular worksheet exploration with customized filters and slicers.
- · Established data connections, integrated tables, and implemented calculations for dynamic user-defined visualizations.

EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant

Nov 2022 - Present

Gurugram, Haryana

- SHL India Pvt Ltd
 - Developed a comprehensive question bank featuring 160 logical and quantitative questions along with 80 data interpretation exercises, designed to enhance analytical and numerical reasoning skills.
 - Developed and tested MS Office simulations, ensuring full quality accuracy by rectifying errors, and played a key role in finalizing over 200 simulation modules.
 - Implemented a comprehensive QA review to identify and rectify any errors or omissions in the final questions prior to the test launch.
 - · Pioneered innovative approaches that delivered high-quality projects ahead of schedule, guaranteeing reliability.

Intern Feb 2022 – June 2022

Surya InfoTech

Remote

- · Leveraged collaborative coding to enhance banking security solutions.
- Utilized programming skills to proactively address and resolve project challenges, ensuring successful completion.

EDUCATION

KNIT Sultanpur

B. Tech in Electronics Engineering

affiliated to AKTU Lucknow Aug 2018 – May 2022

CERTIFICATIONS

- · Business Analysis Fundamentals Udemy
- Power BI SimpliLearn
- · Python Certificate HackerRank
- · Fundamentals of Database and SQL SimpliLearn